let's look at the solution to our BTB
and BHT quiz the question this time is
which BHT entry do we access for each
instruction there are 16 entries in the
phd and we said that we access the BHT
using the lowermost bits of the
instruction address that are not the
same for all instructions in this case
our instruction address has the
following bits for the move instruction
here we have C 0 0 0 because every
instruction is 4 bytes in size the
lowermost 2 bits are never changing they
are always going to be 0 for own
instructions and now because we have 16
Bhd entries we take the next 4 bits and
this is the number of the BHT entry in
this case we are accessing the BHT entry
number 0 now let's look at this other
move instruction here whose address is C
0 0 4 C 0 0 are not changing what is
changing is 4 4 in binary 0 1 0 0 again
we discard these bits because they are
never changing among instructions and
this is the number of the BHT entry so
the entry that we access here is 1 now
you can tell that for instruction 8 here
this is going to be 1 0 so we're going
to access the BHT entry number 2 3 4 5 6
& 7
if we reached 15 we would then wrap
around to 0 but we never reach it so
this is really what we get